ARI KAMLANI

DATA SCIENTIST | TECHNOLOGIST linkedin: @akamlani ← arikamlani.com +1 (415) 926-1221 ← akamlani@gmail.com San Francisco, CA. USA

PROFILE

Data Scientist and former Technologist with 15+ years of overall experience, including a history of delivering strategic large-scale projects in challenging environments. Experienced across the entire lifecycle, from ideation and prototyping through product development and certification. Particularly focused on advancing initiatives for alleviating user and technology pain points. Prior domain expertise includes IoT, Wireless Technology, Reference Semiconductor designs, and Embedded Software.

EDUCATION

Galvanize, San Francisco, CA | Data Science Immersive Bootcamp (Jun 2016-Aug 2016): Data Science Fellow Data ScienceTech Institute (DSTI), Paris, France | Part-Time Data Scientist Designer (Oct 2015-May 2016) General Assembly, San Francisco, CA | Part-Time Data Science (Oct 2014 – Dec 2014) Lehigh University, Bethlehem, PA | Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering (1999)

Select Recent Trainings (Paris, France):

Distributed Computing with Apache Spark (1.6.1) – Scala, Python IBM Analytics Ecosystem SAS Enterprise Miner, Visual Analytics

EXPERIENCE

Inria Research Institute | Sophia Antipolis, France

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

Part-Time Research – STARS (Spatio-Temporal Activity Recognition Systems) Research Team
Computer vision Semantic Scene interpretation per preventive care and diagnosis for the elderly

- Enhanced event recognition models per manually identified zones in the home from underlying events
- Improved structure interpretation of missing ground truth scenarios per more aligned zone detection

Nagra Kudelski Group | San Francisco, CA

2012-2015

Software Expert – Group Incubation & Innovation

Technologist within R&D Innovation Group responsible for future Technology and Application Advancement

- Initiated new concept proposals per Intellectual Property (IP), creation of Patents, and new business units
- Formulated new strategic Partner Vendor relationships to strengthen top tier projects
- Executed multiple technology research & assessment special project directives to strengthen business portfolio
- Led Proof of Concept (POC) designs centered on long-range distance detection, achieving similar results to Active RFID via a Battery-Assisted Passive (BAP) RFID design at a fraction of the cost

SPORTVISION | Mountain View, CA

2011-2012

Embedded Software Consultant – Motorsports Division

Special Projects Consultant reporting to office of CTO for Motorsports (NASCAR Trucks) division, advising in the development of vehicle tracking, local base station communication, and sensor measurement.

- Assess predecessor vehicle tracking technology to improve tracking accuracy during bad weather conditions
- Successfully delivered customized Embedded Linux Kernel (2.6.35) and Root Filesystem (RFS) distribution to improve stability and performance of predecessor system, notably reducing crashes, latency and boot-time
- Provided critical features to diagnose defects in the field and update images remotely during race day

Principal Engineer – Systems Engineering, Cellular Division

Responsible for WiMAX and LTE radio network driver systems software architecture mobile reference designs.

- Guided technology teams per next generation mobile platform processor architecture and requirements
- Directed platform requirements, architecture, and integration of vendor Voice over LTE (VoLTE) stack
- Managed multi-site group coordination per customer (RIM) migration platform architecture from Linux to QNX

Qualcomm | Raleigh, NC

2007-2010

Staff Engineer – Computing and Consumer Division

Responsible for Windows Mobile board support package (BSP) Snapdragon ARM Cortex based reference designs.

- Engaged in cross-disciplinary technical reviews with multi-site technology teams to access processor requirements, identify next generation features, and improve upon the current reference design
- Enhanced systems performance initiatives, to further optimize boot time, perform monitors and latency
- Advised OEMs in custom feature development and in successfully achieving certification requirements

Additional Experiences:

TapRoot Systems, Morrisville, NC | 2003-2007 | Principal Engineer/Technical Lead – Mobile Products and Services Panasonic Mobile Communications, Suwanee, GA | 2000-2003 | Senior Software Engineer – Mobile Platforms Verizon Wireless, Plymouth Meeting, PA | 1999-2000 | RF Systems Performance Engineer – Systems Performance

Technical Skills

Data Analysis Jupyter (IPython Notebook), Yhat Rodeo, R Studio, Zeppelin

Distributed Systems Apache Spark (1.6.1)

SAS SAS Enterprise Miner, SAS Visual Analytics
IBM BigInsights, SPSS Modeler, Bluemix, Watson

Databases SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Programming Python, R, Scala, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS, C, C++, ARM Assembler, VHDL

OOD Modeling UML, OCL

Frameworks Bootstrap, Foundation, Jekyll Project Management Agile Scrum (Pivotal Tracker)

SCM/Tracking Git, Perforce, ClearCase, ClearQuest, SVN, PVCS, Bugzilla

Requirements Management Doors

Operating Systems Linux/Unix, QNX Nucleus Plus, Windows Mobile/WinCE, Symbian

IDE Eclipse, IntelliJ, Spyder, GDB, Trace32 Lauterbauch, QNX Momentics IDE,

MSFT Visual Studio, Platform Builder, ARM Development Suite, Rational Rose RT,

CodeWarrior

Patents

Interference Control in Wireless Communication; United States 9,357,404 (Received: 05/31/2016)
 Device Localization Based on a Learning Model; United States 14/311,077 (Filed: 06/20/2014)